<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spare-Times on Ignacio Delgado</title><link>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/</link><description>Recent content in Spare-Times on Ignacio Delgado</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI Talk at Hackerspace</title><link>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/ai-talk-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/ai-talk-1/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/ai-talk-1/ai.webp" alt="Featured image of post AI Talk at Hackerspace" />&lt;p>(credits to Enrique Domínguez, co-author of the talk)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following is a summary generated by Gemini 1.0 Pro 1M context window, from the transcription retrieved with OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s Whisper from the talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see the talk in Spanish in &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7SLHjoDxL8c" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Youtube&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="summary-of-the-generative-artificial-intelligence-workshop-at-hackerspace-part-1-valencia">Summary of the Generative Artificial Intelligence Workshop at Hackerspace (part 1) Valencia
&lt;/h1>&lt;h2 id="workshop-introduction">Workshop Introduction
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The workshop focused on generative artificial intelligence, covering everything from fundamentals to practical applications. The main objectives included understanding large language models (LLMs), exploring real-world applications, and demonstrating practical implementations. The session aimed to share knowledge and experiences in the field of generative AI, motivating attendees to explore and develop their own projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tools-and-applications-discussed">Tools and Applications Discussed
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="midjourney">MidJourney
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>MidJourney was introduced as an advanced tool for creating images based on textual prompts. This tool stands out for its image quality and accessibility through web interfaces, allowing users to generate art with ease. Despite its advantages, limitations such as restricted customization and occasional errors were mentioned.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="stable-diffusion">Stable Diffusion
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Stable Diffusion was presented as an open-source solution for creating images and texts. Its open-source nature promotes privacy, allows for extensive customization, and has an active community that constantly contributes to the tool&amp;rsquo;s development and improvement. Stable Diffusion operates locally, which is a plus in terms of data control and privacy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="leonardoai">Leonardo.ai
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Leonardo.ai was discussed as a platform based on Stable Diffusion that offers image generation services through prompts. Being a free solution, it facilitates exploration and experimentation in visual content generation, using renewable daily credits for image creation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-aspects-of-generative-artificial-intelligence">Key Aspects of Generative Artificial Intelligence
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="large-language-models-llms">Large Language Models (LLMs)
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The practical use of LLMs for tasks such as language translation and baby name generation was explored in depth. The use of tools like Olama to run language models locally was highlighted, providing greater control and customization over generated results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="practical-applications">Practical Applications
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Practical cases of generative AI application were shared, including the creation of conversational interfaces and the generation of creative content. Personal projects of the presenters were also explored, demonstrating the potential of these technologies in creative and technical fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="projects-at-hackerspace-part-1-valencia-and-future-workshops">Projects at Hackerspace (part 1) Valencia and Future Workshops
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="current-and-future-projects">Current and Future Projects
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The workshop served as a platform to discuss ongoing and future projects at Hackerspace (part 1) Valencia, such as programming workshops, Arduino use, and PCB design with Kikad. The possibility of organizing additional workshops focused on generative artificial intelligence was raised.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="suggestions-for-upcoming-workshops">Suggestions for Upcoming Workshops
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The community expressed interest in delving even deeper into generative artificial intelligence, suggesting future workshops that address more specific practical applications, such as developing Jarvis-style personal assistants and home automation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources-and-recommendations-for-the-community">Resources and Recommendations for the Community
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="learning-sources-and-community">Learning Sources and Community
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>It was recommended to follow specialized YouTubers and participate in online communities to stay up to date with the latest trends and developments in generative AI. Additionally, exploring GitHub to discover relevant projects and tools was suggested, encouraging attendees to actively contribute and participate in these ecosystems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="workshop-conclusion">Workshop Conclusion
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The workshop concluded with thanks to the participants and Hackerspace (part 1) Valencia for providing the space and resources to carry out the session. Attendees were encouraged to continue exploring the field of generative artificial intelligence and to participate in future activities and projects organized by the Hackerspace (part 1).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My First Talk at Google DSC: A Journey in Public Speaking</title><link>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/dsc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/dsc/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had the honor of giving a small talk at a local Developer Student Club (DSC) in collaboration with other universities, including Cartagena&amp;rsquo;s Polytechnic University. It was an &lt;strong>amazing experience&lt;/strong> that left me feeling accomplished and eager for more opportunities to speak publicly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Public speaking is an area where I&amp;rsquo;m actively working to improve:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I enjoy the challenge of speaking in public&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity to share knowledge and connect with others&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Each experience helps me grow more confident&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I hope to give more talks in the near future. Potential venues include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Another DSC event&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Local Hackerspace meetups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other tech community gatherings&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Every opportunity to speak publicly is a step forward in personal and professional growth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hexy: My Journey into Hexapod Robotics</title><link>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/hexy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/hexy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hexy is a small hexapod robot that I purchased and assembled. This project served as an exciting platform for me to delve into the world of robotics and gain hands-on experience with inverse kinematics.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-project">The Project
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Hexy is more than just a toy; it&amp;rsquo;s a sophisticated learning tool that allowed me to explore various aspects of robotics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Assembly&lt;/strong>: I purchased Hexy as a kit and assembled it myself, gaining valuable experience in robot construction.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hardware&lt;/strong>: The robot features a modified Arduino Mega board, which serves as its brain and control center.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Programming&lt;/strong>: I programmed Hexy using C++, honing my skills in embedded systems programming.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Inverse Kinematics&lt;/strong>: Perhaps the most fascinating aspect of this project was learning about inverse kinematics - the mathematical process of determining joint angles to achieve a desired position of the robot&amp;rsquo;s legs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="learning-outcomes">Learning Outcomes
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Working with Hexy has been an incredible learning experience:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Practical Robotics&lt;/strong>: Gained hands-on experience in building and programming a real robot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Arduino&lt;/strong>: Deepened my understanding of Arduino-based systems and their applications in robotics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>C++ for Embedded Systems&lt;/strong>: Improved my C++ programming skills in the context of embedded systems.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Inverse Kinematics&lt;/strong>: Acquired a basic understanding of inverse kinematics and its crucial role in robot movement.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="future-plans">Future Plans
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>While Hexy has already taught me a lot, there&amp;rsquo;s always room for more learning and improvement:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Implement more complex movement patterns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrate sensors for autonomous behavior&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Explore machine learning applications for adaptive locomotion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Hexy has been an invaluable project in my journey into robotics. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about building a cool hexapod; it&amp;rsquo;s about the knowledge gained in mechanics, electronics, and programming. This project has sparked a deeper interest in robotics and laid a foundation for future, more complex robotic endeavors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One from Two: Reviving a Nintendo DS Lite</title><link>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-2.webp" alt="Featured image of post One from Two: Reviving a Nintendo DS Lite" />&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-5.webp"
width="4624"
height="2604"
srcset="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-5_hu461358944615377252.webp 480w, https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-5_hu8267042283548644268.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Fixed Nintendo DS Lite"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I took two broken Nintendo DS Lite consoles and made one that works. It was my first try at fixing electronics, and it worked!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-problem">The Problem
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>My old Nintendo DS Lite had been broken since I was a kid. I wanted to fix it, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-i-fixed-it">How I Fixed It
&lt;/h2>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Getting Parts&lt;/strong>: I bought another broken Nintendo DS Lite cheap. It had different problems from mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mixing Parts&lt;/strong>: I opened up both Nintendo DS Lites. I figured out which parts still worked in each one.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Soldering&lt;/strong>: The hardest part was soldering a tiny switch. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the right tools, but I tried anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Putting It Back Together&lt;/strong>: After soldering, I put all the working parts into one Nintendo DS Lite.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="what-happened">What Happened
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>To my surprise, it worked! When I turned it on and saw it working, I felt really excited. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe I had fixed it on my first try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This project taught me that it&amp;rsquo;s fun to fix old stuff. Sometimes, giving it a try can lead to great results, even if you&amp;rsquo;re not an expert.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pictures">Pictures
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Here are some photos from when I was fixing it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-2.webp"
width="4624"
height="2604"
srcset="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-2_hu13220713626703876616.webp 480w, https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-2_hu18074642327657233496.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Taking Apart the DS"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-3.webp"
width="4624"
height="2604"
srcset="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-3_hu2102023235466601986.webp 480w, https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-3_hu4162144956830125797.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Inside the DS"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-5.webp"
width="4624"
height="2604"
srcset="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-5_hu461358944615377252.webp 480w, https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/nintendo-ds/ds-5_hu8267042283548644268.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="The Fixed DS"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DIY Robots: Hubert and Plotter</title><link>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/robots.webp" alt="Featured image of post DIY Robots: Hubert and Plotter" />&lt;p>This page showcases two small robotics projects I&amp;rsquo;ve created: Hubert, a biped robot, and Plotter, a 2D drawing robot. Both were built using a combination of 3D printed parts and salvaged computer components.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hubert-the-biped-robot">Hubert: The Biped Robot
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Hubert is a modified version of the Zowi biped robot, originally designed by BQ.
&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/robots3.webp"
width="640"
height="640"
srcset="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/robots3_hu12167573502506141505.webp 480w, https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/robots3_hu3495651296972488966.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Plotter the drawing robot"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="100"
data-flex-basis="240px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Key features of Hubert:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Brown in color&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Based on the Zowi biped robot design&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified from the original BQ version&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Controlled by Arduino&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I ended up donating Hubert to my high school, where it can inspire other students interested in robotics.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="plotter-the-2d-drawing-robot">Plotter: The 2D Drawing Robot
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Plotter is a small project that functions like a 2D version of a 3D printer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/robots2.webp"
width="750"
height="563"
srcset="https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/robots2_hu10921900598345006118.webp 480w, https://ignaciodelgado.com/spare-time/robots/robots2_hu12677605609262145993.webp 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Hubert the biped robot"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="319px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Key features of Plotter:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Can draw in 2D when given a pen or pencil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Built using 3D printed parts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Controlled by Arduino&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Plotter can be used for creating simple drawings, signatures, or even as a base for more complex 2D CNC projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="building-process">Building Process
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Both robots were created using a combination of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3D printed parts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scrap computer components&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arduino boards for control&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This approach to building robots demonstrates how you can create interesting and functional projects with a mix of new technology (3D printing) and recycled materials.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These projects show that with some creativity and basic electronics knowledge, you can build fun and educational robots using readily available materials and open-source designs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>